export const quizData =[
    {
        "question": "A flat surface can be produced by a lathe machine, if the cutting tool moves _____",
        "answer": "b) perpendicular to the axis of rotation of workpiece",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) parallel to the axis of rotation of workpiece",
            "b) perpendicular to the axis of rotation of workpiece",
            "c) at an angle of 450",
            "d) none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the function of cone pulley drive in lathe machines?",
        "answer": "b) Change the spindle speed",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Drive the lead screw",
            "b) Change the spindle speed",
            "c) Drive the tail-stock",
            "d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a mechanism for mechanized movements of the carriage along longitudinal axis?",
        "answer": "c) Apron",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Cross-slide",
            "b) Compound rest",
            "c) Apron",
            "d) Saddle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of taper turning process is to ____",
        "answer": "a) reduce the diameter of a workpiece along its length",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) reduce the diameter of a workpiece along its length",
            "b) reduce the diameter by removing material about an axis offset from the axis of workpiece",
            "c) remove the material from end surface of a workpiece",
            "d) all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of bevelling sharp ends of a workpiece is called as ________",
        "answer": "d) chamfering",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) knurling",
            "b) grooving",
            "c) facing",
            "d) chamfering"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In an isolated system, ________ can be transferred between the system and its surrounding.",
        "answer": "d) neither energy nor mass",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) only energy",
            "b) only mass",
            "c) both energy and mass",
            "d) neither energy nor mass"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an extensive property?",
        "answer": "a) Volume",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Volume",
            "b) Pressure",
            "c) Viscosity",
            "d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How is absolute pressure measured?",
        "answer": "a) Gauge pressure + Atmospheric pressure",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Gauge pressure + Atmospheric pressure",
            "b) Gauge pressure â€“ Atmospheric pressure",
            "c) Gauge pressure / Atmospheric pressure",
            "d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The extensive properties of a system, _______",
        "answer": "c) depend upon the mass of the system",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) are independent of the mass of the system",
            "b) depend upon temperature of the system",
            "c) depend upon the mass of the system",
            "d) none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "An isobaric process, has constant _____",
        "answer": "b) pressure",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) density",
            "b) pressure",
            "c) temperature",
            "d) volume"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following energy conversion devices convert heat into work?",
        "answer": "b) I. C engines",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Electrical generators",
            "b) I. C engines",
            "c) Condensers",
            "d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Lancashire boilers are ______",
        "answer": "b) internally fired boilers",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) externally fired boilers",
            "b) internally fired boilers",
            "c) both a. and b.",
            "d) none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Smoke tube boilers have large water to steam ratio, hence _____",
        "answer": "b) are slow in operations",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) have high evaporation rates",
            "b) are slow in operations",
            "c) temperature stresses inducing failure of feed water arrangement are maximum",
            "d) all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are false for reaction turbines?",
        "answer": "c) 1 and 4",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) 1, 2 and 3",
            "b) 2 and 4",
            "c) 1 and 4",
            "d) 1, 2, 3 and 4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In four stroke cycle engine, cycle is completed in ______",
        "answer": "b) two revolutions of the crankshaft",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) two strokes of the piston",
            "b) two revolutions of the crankshaft",
            "c) three strokes of the piston",
            "d) four revolutions of the crankshaft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of bearings are known as anti friction bearings?",
        "answer": "b) Rolling contact bearings",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Sliding contact bearings",
            "b) Rolling contact bearings",
            "c) Both a. and b.",
            "d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In roller bearings which type of rolling elements are used?",
        "answer": "d) All of the above",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
            "a) Cylindrical rollers",
            "b) Taper rollers",
            "c) Spherical rollers",
            "d) All of the above"
        ],
    },

    
        {
            "question": "Why is the load carrying capacity low in ball bearings?",
            "answer": "c) only 4",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) 1 and 3",
                "b) only 1",
                "c) only 4",
                "d) 2 and 4"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Cylindrical roller bearings have greater _____",
            "answer": "c) radial load carrying capacity",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) axial load carrying capacity",
                "b) thrust load carrying capacity",
                "c) radial load carrying capacity",
                "d) all of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements is/are true?",
            "answer": "a) Jaw clutch is a positive clutch",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) Jaw clutch is a positive clutch",
                "b) The power transmitting capacity of a friction clutch is inversely proportional to the coefficient of friction between contacting surfaces",
                "c) Driving and driven plates in friction clutches are held together due to radial force applied by the helical springs",
                "d) All of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Determine torque transmitted on the pinion shaft if torque transmitted on gear shaft is 20 Nm. Consider Gear ratio = 4",
            "answer": "b) 5 Nm",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) 8 Nm",
                "b) 5 Nm",
                "c) 80 Nm",
                "d) 16 Nm"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements is/are true for gear drives?",
            "answer": "b) They are used to transmit power between non-intersecting and parallel shafts",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) They can be used for long centre distances",
                "b) They are used to transmit power between non-intersecting and parallel shafts",
                "c) They cannot be used for high reduction ratios",
                "d) All of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "In which power transmitting drive polygon effect is observed?",
            "answer": "b) Chain drive",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) Belt drive",
                "b) Chain drive",
                "c) Both a. and b.",
                "d) None of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is meant by gear ratio?",
            "answer": "a) The ratio of pinion speed and gear speed",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) The ratio of pinion speed and gear speed",
                "b) The ratio of number of teeth on pinion and number of teeth on gear",
                "c) Both a. and b.",
                "d) None of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which gears are used to connect two intersecting shaft axes?",
            "answer": "c) Bevel gears",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) Crossed helical gear",
                "b) Worm and worm wheel",
                "c) Bevel gears",
                "d) All of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "In stress-strain diagram, up to proportional limit ______",
            "answer": "c) stress is directly proportional to strain",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) stress is inversely proportional to strain",
                "b) force is directly proportional to displacement",
                "c) stress is directly proportional to strain",
                "d) strain is directly proportional to stress"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Deformation per unit length is called as ________",
            "answer": "a) strain",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) strain",
                "b) stress",
                "c) modulus of elasticity",
                "d) none of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following materials do not have a well defined yield point?",
            "answer": "d) All of the above",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) Heat treated steel",
                "b) Concrete",
                "c) Carbon fiber",
                "d) All of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Factor of safety is the ratio of _________",
            "answer": "d) yield strength and working stress",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) working stress and ultimate strength",
                "b) yield strength and endurance strength",
                "c) ultimate strength and yield strength",
                "d) yield strength and working stress"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "The elongation of a bar is 0.5 mm, when a tensile stress of 200 N/mm2 acts on it. Determine original length of a bar if modulus of elasticity is 150 x 103.",
            "answer": "a) 375.93 mm",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
                "a) 375.93 mm",
                "b) 300 mm",
                "c) 360 mm",
                "d) None of the above"
            ]
        }
    
    
]
